<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sandra Chea</title>
    <description>Hello! I'm Sandra Chea, a sophomore attending Caltech and an aspiring electrical engineer. I'm currently interested in circuit and PCB design and really love getting my hands dirty in awesome and innovative electronics hardware! </description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 10:44:06 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 10:44:06 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hydrophone Board</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
 This is the hydrophone board that my partner and I fully designed in Altium. It is mounted onto the autonomous submarine designed by the Caltech Robotics Team. The Caltech Robotics Team participates in an annual competition where autonomous submarines execute a variety of tasks to as many points as possible. One of these tasks includes following pings generated by a pinger. This is where the hydrophone board comes into play. This board first amplifes and reduces noise from the received pinger signals. It then digitially processes them using methods involving sine and cosine tables as well as fourier integrals to compute the ping phase and direction to successfully move in the direction of the pinger. The next steps include implementing inter-submarine communication using a hydrophone transmitter board.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pcb%20design/2020/10/11/hydrophone/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pcb%20design/2020/10/11/hydrophone/</guid>
        
        
        <category>PCB Design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Analog Clock</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
 This is a fully functioning clock consisting of 60 RGB LEDs to display time and three push buttons to set the time.  Using assembly language meant for typical AVR microcontrollers, I programmed and troubleshooted all hardware logic designs of the Caltech20 Microcontroller. The microcontroller had the typical peripherals, including SPI, IO Ports, Timer, and Chip Select and Interrupt, as well as the Caltech 10 CPU. The CPU is a RISC Accumulator based Harvard Architecture CPU, in which I also fully programmed all parts such as the ALU or Program Counter. The simulation image may not mimic a clock too much, but with the remote learning situations, it was the best that could be done. This project was done during the Introduction to Digital Logic and Embedded Systems Course. The next steps are to design the actual board, upload all the written code and have a physical analog clock!
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/class%20project/2020/10/11/analog-clock/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/class%20project/2020/10/11/analog-clock/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Class Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Arduino Projects</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
 These are some preliminary Arduino configurations that I've done over the summer. Although very simple, the purpose of these projects is to explore the peripherals and communication protocols in more depth. The full process included constructing, troubleshooting, and more importantly investigating how information is communicated at a register level. Below are some more configurations. This knowledge was then applied to an avionics platform that can be more effectively discussed in person.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;style&gt;

.imgContainer {
  float : left;

}

  .row::after {
    content : &quot;&quot;;
    clear: both;
    display: table;
  }

&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image123&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;imgContainer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/Arduino_Servo.png&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;imgContainer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/Arduino_Brushless.png&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;imgContainer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/Arduino_DC_Motor.png&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;imgContainer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/Arduino_Stepper.png&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/mini%20projects/2020/10/11/arduino-project/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/mini%20projects/2020/10/11/arduino-project/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Mini Projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wheel Speed Sensors</title>
        <description>&lt;style&gt;

.imgContainer {
  float : left;
  width: 50%;
  padding: 5px;
}

  .row::after {
    content : &quot;&quot;;
    clear: both;
    display: table;
  }

&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image123&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;imgContainer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/tachometer_top.png&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;imgContainer&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/tachometer_bottom.png&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This Wheel Speed Sensors board is implemented onto the electric car designed by the Caltech Racing Team. It essentially serves as the tachometer, measuring how fast the car's wheels are rotating. The implementation will be done with an analog output hall effect sensor as well as two symetrically placed neodymium magnets. The signals received are processed as interrupts into the STM32F469 Microntroller to provide information about the car's RPM. The next steps involve board fabrication as well as troubleshooting.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pcb%20design/2020/10/08/wheel-speed-sensors/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pcb%20design/2020/10/08/wheel-speed-sensors/</guid>
        
        
        <category>PCB Design</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
